<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Info on Na Jin&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://codingnj.github.io/en/series/info/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Info on Na Jin&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Na Jin&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>https://codingnj.github.io/en/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://codingnj.github.io/en/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 21:36:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://codingnj.github.io/en/series/info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Social Security, Medicare Fight Kicks Off With Biden Budget-WSJ</title>
      <link>https://codingnj.github.io/en/posts/info/info0003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 21:36:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://codingnj.github.io/en/posts/info/info0003/</guid>
      <description>Social Security, Medicare Fight Kicks Off With Biden Budget The president is proposing a Medicare solvency plan and warning that Republicans would cut entitlements, a claim Trump rejects
这句话的含义是，总统正在提议一个确保医疗保险（Medicare）财务稳定的计划，并警告说共和党人会削减权利性福利（entitlements），这是特朗普（Trump）所拒绝的主张。
这里：
Medicare solvency plan 指的是一项旨在确保美国医疗保险系统财务上可持续的计划。医疗保险是美国的一项联邦健康保险计划，主要服务于65岁以上的老年人和某些残疾人。 warning that Republicans would cut entitlements 表示总统在提出这个计划的同时，还警告称共和党人可能会削减权利性福利。权利性福利通常指根据法律规定，符合特定条件的人有权获得的福利，如社会保障、医疗保险等。 a claim Trump rejects 指的是特朗普对于共和党人会削减权利性福利这一说法的拒绝或否认。这里暗示了政治上的争论和对立。 综上所述，这句话反映了美国医疗保险系统财务稳定计划的提议，以及围绕这个议题的政治争议。
在这个上下文中，“solvency”和“entitlement”有特定的含义：
Solvency “Solvency”在财务和经济领域中指的是一个个体或机构支付债务的能力，特别是在长期内能够满足其债务义务的能力。在提到“Medicare solvency plan”时，这指的是一项计划，旨在确保美国医疗保险（Medicare）系统财务上的稳定和可持续性，即确保该系统能够长期支付其赔付和运营费用，不会因为资金不足而破产或无法履行其对受益人的义务。
Entitlement “Entitlement”在政策和法律语境中，通常指根据法律或政策规定，个人或团体有权获得的某种福利或服务。这些福利通常是基于特定的资格条件，如年龄、收入或残疾状况。在这里提到的“cut entitlements”（削减权利性福利）意味着减少或限制人们根据这些法律或政策所拥有的获得特定福利（如社会保障金、医疗保险等）的权利。
因此，当总统提出“Medicare solvency plan”并警告共和党可能“cut entitlements”时，这表明了一方面在寻求确保医疗保险系统的财务健康，另一方面则是关于政治争议，即对于是否应该减少公民通过法律有权获得的福利的争论。
WASHINGTON—President Biden’s budget blueprint will kick off an election-year fight over Medicare and Social Security, as the president and his presumed Republican opponent, Donald Trump, scramble to lock down the support of the older voters who could decide which man occupies the Oval Office next year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WSJ More Americans Are Treating Their 401(k)s Like Cash Machines</title>
      <link>https://codingnj.github.io/en/posts/info/info0002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 19:31:12 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://codingnj.github.io/en/posts/info/info0002/</guid>
      <description>More Americans Are Treating Their 401(k)s Like Cash Machines Putting money in Pulling money out The 401(k) is doing double duty as both a retirement account and a source of emergency funds for more Americans.
A record share of 401(k) account holders took early withdrawals from their accounts last year for financial emergencies, according to internal data from Vanguard Group. Overall, 3.6% of its plan participants did so last year, up from 2.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
